环球影业公司
照明  娱乐
通用
图片
克里斯   梅尔
导演
片名: 卑鄙的我2
The title:I'm mean two
卑鄙的我 2
史蒂夫 卡雷尔
克里斯汀
便雅悯 布拉特
米兰达
罗素  布兰德
史蒂夫 库根
肯 郑
最高机密调查实验室 北极圈
Top secret investigation laboratory, The Arctic Circle
最高机密研究实验室
嗯?
Huh?
都已经三周了 我们还是毫无头绪
Three weeks, and we're still no closer to cracking this.
好吧 把他叫来
Right, bring him in!
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
艾格尼丝 生日快乐
Agnes, Happy birthday.
这是有史以来最棒的派对
This is the best party ever!
耶
Yeah!
哈
Ha!
不 龙来了
Oh, no! A dragon is approaching!
不要怕 英勇的骑士来救我们了
Fear not, for here come the gallant knights to save us.
耶
Yay!
不 不 你说"她不能来"是什么意思?
No, no, no. What do you mean she's not coming?
我家后院的小女孩们
I have a backyard full of these little girls
都在等着仙女姐姐的到来呢
who are counting on a visit from a fairy princess.
好疼 停下
Hurts! Stop it!
听着 我不要退款 我要仙女姐姐 求求你们了
Listen! I don't want a refund, I want the fairy princess, please!
求求你们了
Please, I'm begging you.
知道吗? 你破坏了小女孩们的愿望
You know what? I hope that you can sleep at night,
你晚上都会睡不安稳的
you crusher of little girls' dreams!
哦
Ooh, ooh!
仙女姐姐什么时候来?
When's the fairy princess coming?
她随时都可能出现
Any minute now!
耶
Yay!
拖住她们
Stall them!
魔术表演
The magic show
哦
Ooh!
哇 等一下 好了
Whoa! Whoa, okay! Okay, all right.
魔术表演到此为止
That's enough of the magic show.
啊
Aw!
等等 你们听到了吗?
Wait, did you hear that?
听起来像是魔法烟雾弥漫在空中
It sounded like the twinkling sounds of magical fairy dust.
是仙女姐姐来了
It's the fairy princess! She's coming!
看啊
Look!
- 嗯? 哦 - 嗯?
- Huh? Oh! - Eh?
啊
Ow!
Ow.
格鲁小叮当来了
It is I, Gruzinkerbell,
我可是最最厉害的仙女
the most magical fairy princess of all!
我是来祝福艾格尼丝小公主
And I am here to wish Princess Agnes
生日快乐的
a very happy birthday!
你为什么那么胖?
How come you're so fat?
因为
Because
我的房子是用糖果做的
my house is made of candy,
有时候遇上了麻烦我就会不停地吃糖
and sometimes I eat instead of facing my problems!
你为什么...
How come you have. . .
好了 该吃蛋糕了
Okay, time for cake.
耶
Yay!
谢谢你 格鲁小叮当 你是最棒的仙女
Thank you, Gruzinkerbell! You're the best fairy princess ever!
不用谢 小姑娘
You are welcome, little girl!
我知道是你 格鲁 我只是假装给其他小朋友看的
I know it's really you, Gru. I'm just pretending for the other kids.
你好啊 格鲁 你真是派对之王
Hey there, Gru. Mr. Life of the Party!
你好 吉莉安
Hello, Jillian.
我想去钓那个帅哥
So, I'm gonna go out on a limb here,
- 不过我的朋友纳塔利可是单身已久 而且... - 啊
- but my friend Natalie is recently single, and...- Oop.
不 不 不 别钓帅哥 没帅哥
No, no, no, get off the limb right now. No limb.
别这样 她很狂野的
Come on, she's a riot!
她会唱卡拉OK 还有很多空闲时间
She sings karaoke, she has a lot of free time,
她不在乎对方相貌...
looks aren't that important to her. . .
不用 吉莉安 真的不用介绍了 真的 我这样挺好
No, Jills, that is not happening. Seriously, I'm fine.
那好吧 不说纳塔利了 那我的表姐琳达怎么样?
Okay, fine, forget Natalie. How about my cousin Linda?
不用
No!
哦 我还认识一个女人 她丈夫最近去世了...
Oh! Oh! I know someone whose husband just died. . .
抱歉 没看到你站在那儿
I'm sorry, I did not see you there.
又没看到
Or there.
不明物体
Unidentified object
凯尔? 你在哪?
Kyle? Kyle?
凯尔 停 不要在喇叭花丛里拉屎
Kyle, no! Do not do your business on the petunias!
目标锁定
target
去弗雷德的花园 尽情释放吧
There you go. Those are Fred's, go crazy.
这才乖
Good boy!
格鲁先生吗?
Mr. Gru?
我可没... 怎么了?
I didn't...What? Yes?
嗨 我是反恶人联盟的露西·维尔德探员
Hi! Agent Lucy Wilde of the AVL.
哦 拿反了
Oh, whoops!
不好意思 你得跟我走一趟
Sorry, you're gonna have to come with me.
哦 抱歉 我... 冰冻射线
Oh, sorry, I...freeze ray!
你应该先出招
You know, you really should announce
再喊招式的 格鲁先生
your weapons after you fire them, Mr. Gru.
比如...
For example. . .
口红镭射枪
Lipstick taser!
哦 太有效果了
Oh, it works so good.
天啊
Man!
猪一样重
Large person.
哦 抱歉
Oh, sorry.
- 给我进去... - 嗯?
- Get in there...- Huh?
你这个大块头
you big man!
老大
Boss!
嗯? 哦
Uh? Huh!
哇
Whoa!
嗯?
Huh?
啊呜
Ah! Whoo!
哦
Ooh!
啊
Oh!
嗯? 呱呱
Huh? Ah. Quack, quack!
哇
Wow!
这是哪里?
What? Where?
啊 脚麻了
Whoa, foot is asleep.
啊 抓心挠肝啊
Ah, pins and needles!
下午好 古鲁先生
Good afternoon, Mr. Gru.
嗯
Eh.
很抱歉用这种方式把你请来
I apologize for our methods in getting you here.
我可不抱歉 我巴不得再来一次
I don't. I'd do it again in a heartbeat.
说实话 每一分每一秒都我都很享受
I am not gonna lie, I enjoyed that.
事实上这让我心跳加速
Every second of it. Gave me a bit of a buzz, actually.
够了 维尔德探员
That's enough, Agent Wilde.
抱歉 长官
Sorry, sir.
这简直是胡闹
Okay, this is bogus!
我不知道你们觉得自己是干嘛的 但是...
I don't know who you people think you are, but. . .
我们是反恶人联盟
We are the Anti-Villain League.
一个致力于打击世界级犯罪的机密组织
An ultra-secret organization dedicated to fighting crime on a global scale.
有人抢银行 我们不感兴趣 有人杀了人 我们可不愿意管
Rob a bank, we're not interested. Kill someone, not our deal.
但如果你想融化北极冰盖 或者让富士山蒸发
But you want to melt the polar ice caps, or vaporize Mount Fuji,
还有偷走月亮...
or even steal the Moon. . .
我们可就要管管了
Then we notice.
首先 你们没有证据那是我干的
First of all, you got no proof that I did that.
其次 我偷了月亮之后又把它还回去了
Second, after I did do that, I put it back!
这我们都知道 格鲁先生
We're well aware of that, Mr. Gru.
所以我们才找你来
That's why we brought you here.
我是联盟的主席 赛拉斯·斯波顿
I am the League's director, Silas Ramsbottom.
斯"屁股"
Bottom.
真好笑
Hilarious.
维尔德探员?
Agent Wilde?
该我了? 哦
Oh, me now? Ah.
最近 一个高级机密实验室
Um, recently, an entire top-secret lab
从北极圈莫名消失了
disappeared from the Arctic Circle.
整个实验室一下子...
Yeah, the entire lab, just. . .
消失了 他们去哪里了?
gone. Where did it go?
不关我的事
I don't care.
嗯 这个实验室研究的
Hmm. The lab was devoted to experiments
是一种变形血清 叫PX-41
involving PX-41, a transmutation serum.
你问PX-41是什么? 嗯 它可是极危险的 看吧
What is PX-41, you ask? Mmm, it's pretty bad. Look.
啊
Ah!
哦 小兔子一般都不会这样
Huh, you usually don't see that in bunnies.
如你所见 PX-41血清如果落到坏人手里
As you can see, in the wrong hands, the PX-41 serum
它就会变成一种毁灭性的武器
could be the most devastating weapon on Earth.
不过好在它的化学踪迹很特殊
Fortunately, it has a very distinct chemical footprint.
使用最新型的化学成分跟踪技术
And using the latest chem-tracking technology,
我们在天堂购物中心发现了它的踪迹
we found traces of it in the Paradise Mall.
购物中心?
A mall?
是的 而且我们相信
Precisely. And we believe that one of these
商场里的某个店主就是犯罪分子
shop owners is a master criminal.
你就要到那里
And that's where you come in.
作为一个"前"恶人 你了解恶人的思想和行为
As an ex-villain, you know how a villain thinks, how a villain acts.
我们计划将你送入商场
The plan is to set you up undercover
当卧底 然后我们就能...
at a shop in the mall, where hopefully we'll be able to. . .
好了 我明白了
Okay, I see where this is going,
你们说的是"碟中谍"里的那一套 但我不同意
with all the Mission: Impossible stuff, but no. No!
我是三个孩子的父亲 还是个遵纪守法的商人
I'm a father now. And a legitimate businessman.
我正在生产美味的果酱和果冻
I am developing a line of delicious jams and jellies.
"果酱和果冻"?
"Jams and jellies"?
哦 怎么了 就是果酱和果冻
Oh, attitude! That's right!
好了 我不感兴趣
So, thanks, but no thanks.
有个小建议 下次想要请人来能不能不要用电击 然后绑架来
And here's a tip. Instead of tasing people and kidnapping them,
你们可以给他打个电话
maybe you should just give them a call!
过得愉快 羊屁股先生
Good day, Mr. Sheepsbutt.
是斯波顿
Ramsbottom.
就像这样就好听了似的
Oh, yeah, like that's any better.
哈哈
Hello.
听着 也许我不该这么说
Look, I probably shouldn't be saying this,
但是你恶人当得真是太好了
but your work as a villain was kind of amazing.
所以如果你想回来大干一番
So, if you ever wanna get back to doing something awesome,
给我们打电话
give us a call.
嘿 我都说了让你们先睡
Hey, I told you guys to get to bed.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
你的约会怎么样?
So, when you going on your date?
什么?
What?
不记得了吗 吉莉安小姐给你安排了一个相亲
Remember, Miss Jillian said she was arranging a date for you.
哦 她有点疯疯癫癫 我没去约会
Yeah, well, she is a nut job, and I'm not going on any date.
为什么? 你害怕了?
Why not? Are you scared?
嘿 你们看电视上的登月节目了吗?
Hey, did you guys see the Moon Landing on TV?
看了 真不敢相信 太酷了
Yeah, I can't believe it. It's so cool!
打扰一下? 丽莎?
Excuse me? Lisa?
昨天我和比利聊天了
I was talking to Billy the other day.
不可能
No way!
他好帅
He is so cute.
嘿 丽莎 我想问你想不想...
Ah. Hey, Lisa, I was wondering if you. . .
哦 格鲁碰了丽莎 格鲁碰了丽莎
Ew! Gru touched Lisa! Gru touched Lisa!
哦
Ew!
丽莎被格鲁碰到了
Lisa's got Gruties!
害怕什么? 女人? 不 太搞笑了
Scared? Of what? Women? No! That's bonkers!
我只是对约会不感兴趣 就这样 谈话结束
I just have no interest in going on a date, that's all. Case closed.
我不害怕女人 也不怕约会
I'm not scared. Of women. Or dates.
睡觉了
Let's go to bed.
晚安 伊迪丝
Good night, Edith.
晚安 玛尔戈 喔 喔 喔
Good night, Margo. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
等一下 你在给谁发短信?
Hold the horses. Who are you texting?
没谁 就是一个朋友叫艾弗里
No one. Just my friend Avery.
艾弗里? 男孩还是女孩?
Avery. Avery? Is that a girl's name or a boy's name?
有关系吗?
Does it matter?
不 没关系 除非是个小男孩
No, no, it doesn't matter unless it's a boy!
我知道你为什么是男的
I know what makes you a boy.
啊
Uh, ooh,
是吗?
you do?
因为你有光头
Your bald head.
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
它很光滑
It's really smooth.
有时候我看着它 想象着有小鸡破壳而出
Sometimes I stare at it, and imagine a little chick popping out.
叽叽叽
Peep peep peep.
晚安 艾格尼丝
Good night, Agnes.
不要长大
Never get older.
果酱制作区
¹û½´ÖÆ×÷Çø
嘿 哦
Hey, oh!
嗯...
Uh. . .
好的
Okay, okay.
嘿 堤姆 发型不错
Hey, Tim, nice haircut!
唐尼 坚持就是胜利 快到周五了
Donnie, hang in there, baby! It's almost Friday.
今天的产量怎么样 唐尼博士?
So, how's today's batch, Dr. Donnie?
我升级了配方
I developed a new formula
这样就能把所有莓子
which allowed me to get every known
混合成一种果冻
kind of berry into one flavor of jelly.
太美味了
That tastes good!
我喜欢这口味
I love the flavor of that!
很难吃 是吧?
It's horrible, isn't it?
不
No, no!
我们已经有很大进步了
Oh, we're making great progress!
尝尝看
Here, try some of this.
嗯
Mmm.
啊
Ah.
哇
Whoa.
就算大家都不喜欢 也不太表它不好吃
Okay, just because everybody hates it, doesn't mean it's not good!
听着 格鲁
Listen, Gru.
有件事情
There's something I've been meaning
我早都想跟你说了
to talk to you about for some time now.
什么事啊?
What? What's wrong?
嗯...
Um. . .
我怀念作恶的日子
I miss being evil.
那些阴谋诡计和犯罪计划 才是我人生的意义
Sinister plots, large-scale crimes, it's what I live for.
那些才是我们的未来 而不是生产果冻 对吧?
I mean, don't you think there's more to our future than jelly?
我还打算生产果酱的
Well, I'm also considering a line of jams.
嗯 是这样的 格鲁
Um, the thing is, Gru,
别人向我伸出了橄榄枝
I've had an offer of employment elsewhere.
唐尼博士
Dr. Nefario!
别这样 你在开玩笑 是吧?
Come on, you're kidding, right?
这对我来说是个好机会
It's a great opportunity for me.
更大的实验室 更坏的计划
Bigger lab, more evil,
还有牙医
full dental.
好吧
Very well.
那让我们给你办一场像样的欢送会吧
Let us give you the proper send-off.
小伙伴们
Minions!
向唐尼博士致以最崇高的敬意
The highest honor awarded to Dr. Nefario
感谢他多年来的奉献
for your years of service,
放21次臭屁致敬
the 21-fart gun salute!
嗯 怎么多放了一次
Uh, I counted 22.
再见了 朋友们
Farewell, my friends.
还需要一段时间
This may take a while.
大家去干活吧
Go about your business.
我都开始想你们了
I miss you already!
嗯?
Huh?
嗯
Huh.
我们真的要这么做?
Are you sure we should be doing this?
是的 这是为他好
Yes, it's for his own good.
不好
No.
吓人
Scary.
古怪
Weird.
怎么了?
What is that?
早上好 姑娘们 我有事情要宣布
Good morning, girls! I have an announcement to make.
嘿 你看起来像那个明星?
Hey, what celebrity do you look like?
嗯 我像布鲁斯·威利斯("虎胆龙威"男主角)
Uh, Bruce Willis.
才不像
Mmm, no.
你像矮胖子 (童谣里的滑稽角色)
Humpty Dumpty!
他像咕噜 ("指环王"里的怪物)
Ooh, Gollum!
好了 你们在干嘛?
Okay, what are you doing?
我们在给你注册交友网站
We're signing you up for online dating!
哦 好吧 什么? 不 不
Oh, okay. What? No, no, no.
别这样 会很好玩的
Oh, come on. It's fun.
你也该找个对象了
And it's time for you to get out there.
不 没人需要找对象 没人
No! Stop! No one is ever getting out there! Ever!
好了 我要宣布我的事情了
Oh! Okay, now for the announcement.
我找了份新工作
I have accepted a new job.
哇 真的吗?
Whoa! Really?
嗯 一家秘密机构聘请我
Yes, I have been recruited by a top-secret agency
去当卧底拯救世界
to go undercover and save the world!
你要当间谍?
You're gonna be a spy?
当然了 宝贝
That's right, baby!
格鲁要东山再起啦
Gru's back in the game.
跑车 手枪 还有全套装备
With gadgets and weapons and cool cars. The whole deal.
太棒了
Awesome!
你真的会拯救世界吗?
Are you really gonna save the world?
是的 我会的
Yes. Yes, I am.
啊
Ah!
嗯
Hmm.
"烘焙时光"
"Bake My Day. "
唉
Blech.
好了 这是我在网上找的蛋糕食谱
All right, here is the cupcake recipe I got off the Internet.
别把巧克力屑弄洒了
And don't go nuts with the sprinkles!
啊
Whoo.
我没想到会这样 对吧?
I wasn't expecting that. Or was I?
哦 你有点... 有点...
Ooh. You got...you got a little. . .
我来帮你擦
Here, I'll get it.
哦
Oh.
好像越抹越多啊
It's just spreading.
好了 我自己来 住手
All right, all right. I got it! Stop it!
哦
Oh.
那还是你自己来吧
I'll let you get it.
嗯 你刚刚看到的那些
Yeah, what you just saw there was a little
都是我新发明的招数
something new I've been working on.
它融合了柔术 近身格斗 阿芝特克武术
It's a combination of Jujitsu, Krav Maga, Aztec warfare
和小丑舞蹈的精华
and krumping.
但是这很奇怪 你怎么会在这里?
Okay, that's weird. Why are you here?
赛拉斯派我来的 我是你的新搭档
On assignment from Silas. I'm your new partner.
耶
Yay!
什么? "耶"什么"耶"
What? No, no "yay".
羊屁股先生可没告诉我还有搭档
Ramsbottom didn't say anything about a partner.
可能是因为你有案底的原因
Well, it seems that because of your checkered past,
所以别人都不愿意和你合作
everyone else refused to work with you.
于是我毛遂自荐了
But not me. I stepped up.
我是新手 所以其实你可以指挥我
And I'm new, so I kind of have to do what they tell me anyway.
你好
Walla!
呀
Ya!
啊
Aah!
你认识他吗?
Do you know this guy?
是的 他是我的手下
Yes, he's one of my minions.
哦 抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
失礼了
I should have known.
你可以走了
You are free to go.
嗯? 啊
Uh? Ah!
干杯
Kampai!
哦
Oh!
戴夫啊...
Dave. . .
呼叫戴夫
Earth to Dave!
嗯?
Huh?
你该走了
You can leave now.
哦...
Oh, uh. . .
什么情况? 名单上都有谁?
So, what do we got? Who's on the list?
读给我听
Fire them at me.
第一位嫌疑人是海达·布朗托夫特
First suspect, Hedda Blumentoft,
"妈咪世界"鲜花店的老板
proprietor of Mum's the Word Floral Shop.
不是她
No, not her.
好吧 那下一个...
Okay, moving on. . .
"填充熊宝宝"商店的店主查德·肯尼
Chuck Kinney, owner of Stuff-A-Bear.
哦
Ooh.
他也不是
I don't think so.
有人吗?
Hello?
早上好 朋友们
Buenos d¨ªas, my friends!
我是爱德华多·佩雷斯
I am Eduardo Perez,
是对面莎莎舞餐厅的老板
owner of Salsay Salsa restaurant, across the mall.
现在我们还供应早餐 你是?
Now open for breakfast. And you are?
我是格鲁 她是露西 但是我们还没开门
Gru. And this is Lucy. And we are closed.
一会会就好
This is just going to take un momento.
我要举办一场盛大的"五月五日节"派对(墨西哥的一个节日)
I am throwing a big Cinco de Mayo party,
我要订200个你们这最好的小蛋糕
and I am going to need 200 of your best cupcakes
上面插上墨西哥小旗
decorated with the Mexican flag.
看起来就和这个差不多
It looks something like this.
怎么样?
What do you think?
- 哦 - 哦
- Ooh. - Oh.
不要看他
Look away!
哇 哇
You, whoo.
好了 我得走了 就这么说好了 我下周来取蛋糕
Anyway, I have to go. It's all settled. I'll pick them up next week!
祝你们愉快 有空过来玩 好吧?
Have a good day. Come by if you get a chance, okay?
欢迎加入商场大家庭
And welcome to the mall family.
他是埃尔马乔
El Macho.
什么?
What?
不可能啊
But it couldn't be.
什么不可能?
What? What couldn't be?
那个人很像一个叫埃尔马乔的恶棍
That guy looks exactly like a villain named El Macho.
那还是20年前的事
From about 20 years ago.
他心狠手辣
He was ruthless!
十分危险
He was dangerous.
他就像他的名字一样 非常霸道
And as the name implies, very macho.
他因为赤手空拳去打劫而出名
He had a reputation for pulling off heists using only his bare hands!
但就像所有英雄的悲剧 埃尔马乔传奇很快就陨落了
But sadly, like all the greats, El Macho was gone too soon.
他死的方式也是最霸气的
He died in the most macho way possible.
他骑着鲨鱼
Riding a shark
胸前绑着250磅的炸药
with 250 pounds of dynamite strapped to his chest
冲到了爆发的火山口
into the mouth of an active volcano!
真是惊心动魄
It was glorious.
嗯 听起来埃尔马乔肯定是死了
Yeah, sounds like El Macho's pretty dead.
他的尸体一直没有被发现 一直也没
They never found the body. Oh, no.
只找到了一撮烧焦了的胸毛
All that was ever retrieved was a pile of singed chest hair.
那张脸 他肯定是埃尔马乔
But that face! It has got to be El Macho!
那我们偷偷溜进他的餐厅怎么样? 今晚就去?
Then what do you say you and I break into his restaurant? Tonight?
嗯 好的 因为如果这里
Yes, that's good, because I am telling you,
有个人有PX-41血清
if anybody in this place has the PX-41 serum,
那肯定是他
it's him.
好了 做完作业 穿上睡衣 刷好牙 该睡觉啦
All right, all right, homework done, pajamas on, teeth brushed, time for bed.
着什么急啊?
What's the big hurry?
我还有很多工作要做
I just have a lot of work to do.
工作 什么工作?
Work, what kind of work?
非常重要的工作
Very important business.
抱一抱 亲一亲
So, hugs, kisses.
晚安 好梦 别让那些啥啥啥打扰了你们的梦乡
Good night, sleep tight, don't let the bedbugs blah-blah-blah.
啊
Whoa!
但是你答应过我
But you said you'd help me practice
帮我练习母亲节表演的
my part for the Mother's Day show.
好吧 让我听听 抓紧时间
Fine, fine. Let me hear it. Quickly.
她亲吻我的小伤口 她给我梳辫子
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair.
我的母亲是无与伦比的
My mother is beyond compare.
我们爱你到永远
We love you, mothers, everywhere.
啊 这真是很奇特的表演
Wow! That was something else.
我很喜欢你结尾的微笑
I really liked the way you smiled at the end.
我们再来一遍
Let's try this one more time,
这次别模仿僵尸了 好吗?
but a teensy bit less like a zombie, okay?
好吧
Okay.
她亲吻我的小伤口 她给我梳辫子...
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair. . .
完美 该睡觉了
Perfect! Time to go.
我觉得我不应该去表演
I don't think I should do this.
怎么了? 为什么不去?
Well, what do you mean? Why not?
我都没有妈妈
I don't even have a mom.
表演节目不一定必须真的有妈妈
Well, you don't need one to do the show.
就像你在退伍军人联欢会上表演
I mean, you did the Veterans Day Pageant
也不用非要打过仗啊
and you haven't been in combat.
这是两码事
This is different.
好吧 那你可以发挥一下你的想象力
Okay, well, then maybe you can just use your imagination.
你是说要我假装我有妈妈?
You mean I pretend I have a mom?
嗯 对吧? 这样就可以了 是吧?
Yes, right? You can do that, can't you?
是的 我一直都是这样
Yeah! I do that all the time.
谢谢了 格鲁
Thanks, Gru!
嘿
Hey!
好了 嘿 停 停
All right. Hey, hey, no, no! No.
嘿 停一下
Hey. Hey, please.
凯文和杰里 去照顾小女孩们 明白吗?
Kevin, Jerry, watch the girls for me, okay?
戴夫和图尔特 跟我来 这边走
Dave, Stuart, come this way! With me! Come on!
走了
Come on!
嗯嗯
Mmm-mmm!
哦
Oh!
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
嗯?
Huh?
- 别怕 - 不怕
- Oca! - Oca!
看你吓的
Looka too!
嗯?
Huh?
莎莎舞餐厅
Dining room of salsa.
我们是忍者 悄无声息
We're stealth ninjas. We make no sound.
好的 明白
Right. Gotcha.
呀
Ya!
来吧 埃尔马乔 你要倒霉了
All right, El Macho. You're going down.
- 等一下 - 怎么了?
- Wait! Wait. - What?
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
我在检查这里有没有激光警报装置
I'm checking for laser beam alarm triggers.
这是家餐厅
It's a restaurant!
永远都被能对陷阱
You never know what kind of booby traps
掉以轻心 嗯? 对吧
this guy could have set. Huh? Come on.
这里没有陷阱
There are no booby traps.
哈 说中了吧
Ha! Booby!
哦 是一只鸡
Oh. There's a chicken.
你迷路了吗 小兄弟?
Are you lost, little guy?
你肯定是迷路了
You must be lost.
哈 这就是他的看门狗
Ha! Some guard dog.
帮我把它赶走 帮我把它赶走
Get it off of me! Get it off of me!
啊
Aah!
抓到你了
I got you!
我来了
I got it!
哈
Ha!
哦
Oh!
这只鸡怎么回事?
What is wrong with that chicken?
嘿 这鸡仔是疯子
Hey, that pollo is loco.
不是吗?
No?
好了 我们走
Okay, let's go.
你发现什么了吗?
Are you getting anything?
还没有
No, not yet.
但是你用这个X光护目镜可能会发现点什么
But, hey, maybe you can find something with these X-ray goggles.
唉
Bah.
护目镜怎么样? 快说说
How are they working? Tell me! Tell me!
啊 哇
Aah! Oof!
怎么了? 有事吗?
What's wrong? Is something wrong?
那画面真是灼伤我双眸啊
That's an image I'll never get out of my brain. Blech!
我就知道
I knew it!
血清在里面
The serum is in here!
哦 那我们快拿走它
Ooh, then let's get it.
终于要成功了
This is going to be good!
啊
Ah.
啊哈
Ah-ha!
什么?
What?
辣酱
À±½´
辣酱?
Salsa?
怎么这样
Aw, man.
哦
Oh.
今晚有人将死
Somebody's going to die tonight.
波立特啊
Pollito!
他们对你做了什么? 波立特 你没事吧?
What did they do to you? Pollito? Can you hear me?
谁会对可爱的小鸡下此狠手?
Who would do this to such a sweet little chicken?
怎么? 谁在那里?
What? Who's there?
哦哦
Mmm-mmm.
你自己出来? 还是我进去抓你?
You coming out? Or am I gonna go in?
呀
Yah!
嗯?
Huh?
别跑
Stop!
我的眼睛
My eyes!
格鲁 赶紧呼叫你的小伙伴们
Gru, call one of your munchkins!
我们被发现了 快来接我们
We've been spotted! Come get us!
嗯? 嘿
Huh? Hey!
啊
Ah!
车技真不错
Hmm, subtle.
在这边 这边
Over here! Over here!
在...
Over. . .
这边
here.
抓住了
Hold tight!
啊
Aah!
抓到你们了
I have you now!
耶 卖冰淇淋的
Yay! Ice cream!
嗯?
Huh?
好了 他来了
All right, there he is.
八号嫌疑人弗洛伊德·依格桑
Suspect number eight, Floyd Eaglesan.
哦 好吧
Oh, okay.
你能不能去近一点 走吧
See if you can get closer. Go, go.
好了
All right.
这是...
What the. . .
警告:巨烫无比
Warning: extremely hot!
哦 不 糟了
Oh, no. That's not good.
啊
Whoa!
嘿 怎么回事?
Hey, uh, what?
哦
Oh!
嘿 格鲁
Hey, Gru!
哦 姑娘们 你们在这里干什么?
Oh, girls! What are you doing here?
我们想去看看你工作
Well, we thought we'd come visit you at work.
你躲在垃圾桶里拯救世界?
So, you're saving the world in a garbage can?
太逗了
Funny.
嘿 你在这儿
Hey! There you are.
哦 她们是谁?
Oh. Who's this?
露西 这是我的女儿们 玛尔戈 伊迪丝和艾格尼丝
Lucy, these are my girls, Margo, Edith and Agnes.
姑娘们 这是露西 这是我的女儿
Girls, Lucy. Lucy, girls.
- 你好 - 嗨
- Hello. - Hi.
你结婚了吗?
Are you single?
哦 天啊
Oh! Goodness.
嘿 我有个主意 既然我和露西还有很多工作要做
Oh, hey! I have an idea. Since Lucy and I have lots of work to do,
- 你们去商场里逛一逛怎么样? - 拜
- why don't you girls go and explore the mall? - Bye!
给你们点钱 去买点那些没用的玩意儿吧
Here is some money, go buy some useless mall junk.
发带什么的...
Some headbands and. . .
你会和露西结婚吗?
Are you gonna marry Lucy?
你疯了吗? 不会 她只是和我一块工作
Are you out of your gourd? No! She just works with me.
但是你爱她啊
Plus, you love her.
你爱她 你爱她 你就是就是很爱她
You love her! You love her! You really, really love her!
你们会结婚的
And you're gonna get married!
停 这首歌是骗人的
Okay, stop. This is a song of lies.
我会是婚礼上的小天使
And I will be the flower girl!
我根本不喜欢她 快去玩吧
I don't even like her. Now, go have fun!
差点忘了 抱一个
Almost forgot. Hugs!
好好拯救世界吧 拜
Good luck saving the world. Bye.
拜 格鲁
Bye, Gru!
小孩子就这样嘛 她们多有趣
Kids, right? They're funny.
你的女儿们真的很喜欢你
Those girls totally adore you.
你一定是个好爸爸
I bet you're a fun dad.
哈
Huh.
我是个好爸爸
I am pretty fun.
你这算是偷吗?
Is that stealing?
我许的愿望就是得到很多硬币 所以这不算是偷
Not if my wish was that I would get a lot of free coins.
啊
Whoa!
眼镜很酷
Cool glasses.
哦
Oh.
我叫安东尼奥
I'm Antonio.
我叫玛尔戈
I'm Margo.
我正想去吃块饼干 要不要一起来?
I was just going to get a cookie. Care to join me?
好的
Uh, sure.
我叫玛尔戈
I'm Margo.
我一会儿跟你们汇合
Um, I'll catch up with you guys later.
拜
Bye!
我能第一个说"恶心"吗
Can I be the first to say, "Ew! "
我们得告诉格鲁
We gotta go tell Gru!
鹰发俱乐部
Eagle club
好了 我进去了
All right, I'm going in.
一旦感应到血清的痕迹 你皮带扣里的感应器
If it picks up any traces of the serum, the sensor in your belt buckle
就会发出这样的声音...
will make a sound like this. . .
咪喵 咪喵
Mee-maw! Mee-maw!
- 咪喵 咪喵 - 好了
- Mee-maw! Mee-maw! - Okay!
知道了 知道了
I get it. I get it.
欢迎来到鹰发俱乐部
Welcome to Eagle Hair Club.
你是该出现了
It's about time you showed up,
格鲁先生
Mr. Gru.
你知道我的名字?
You know my name?
当没头发的人进入中心时
When someone moves into the mall who is folically-challenged,
我的任务就是彻底了解他们
I make it my business to know all about them.
你是秃头 很容易暴露你
You are bald, and that is bad.
给你戴上 亲爱的
There you go, my sweet.
目前没反应
I'm getting nothing so far.
你可能得四处转转
I think you need to move around.
哇哦 这个看起来很有趣 这是什么?
Wow, this looks interesting. What is it?
你是艺术爱好者吗?
I take it you're an art lover?
没有血清
No serum.
不算是吧
Yeah, not so much.
这个造型独特的小玩意怎么样呢?
Oh, how about this impressive trinket?
我从不叫它小玩意 格鲁先生
I'd hardly call it a trinket, Mr. Gru.
- 没反应 - 国际上...
- Nothing. - The International. . .
我不感兴趣
Yeah, I don't care.
咪喵 咪喵
Mee-maw! Mee-maw!
慢着 感应到东西了 在墙后面
Hold on, I'm picking up something. Behind that wall!
啊 这里有什么?
Ah, and what do we have here?
这些是我的假发样品 你应该买一个
These are my trial wigs. You should take one.
不用了 话说墙的另一边有什么?
No, thanks. So, what's on the other side of the wall?
喂 看着我 专心点
Here you are! Look at me! Focus!
怎么了格鲁?
Gru?
我保证这顶假发会让你从奇丑无比
I promise that this wig will transform you from ugly
变得魅力撩人
to irresistible.
玛尔戈有男朋友了
Margo has a boyfriend!
而且他们约会去了
And they're going on a date!
约会? 男朋友?
Date? Boyfriend?
什么情况?
What?
她在那
There she goes!
哦 你真是太幽默了
Oh, you're so funny.
好恶心
Gross!
- 快看 他们恋爱了 - 不不不
- Look, they're in love. - Oh, no, no, no.
别这么说 不不 不会的
Do not say that. No, no, no.
我的梦想是将来以打电子游戏为生
And my dream is to one day play video games for a living.
哇哦
Wow.
你真是太有内涵了
You're so complicated.
玛尔戈啊
Margo.
这怎么回事?
What is going on here?
格鲁 他叫安东尼奥 我的名字是玛尔戈
Oh, Gru, se llama Antonio. Me llamo Margo.
我叫羊驼喇嘛叮叮叮 管他呢? 我们走
Me llama-lama ding-dong. Who cares? Let's go.
哇哦
Whoa!
周二儿童免费
Kids eat free on Tuesdays.
好 棒极了
Yay, Pop!
太炫了
That's awesome!
- 很高兴再见面 我的朋友 - 哈 呵呵
- So good to see you again, mi compadre! - Ha! Yeah.
看来你已经认识我父亲了
Oh, I see you have already met my father.
什么? 父亲?
What? Father?
对啊 看我们的世界是多么小啊?
Si. Look at this crazy small world we live in, eh?
来 坐 我给你上点吃的
Come, sit, let me get you something.
- 哦 小公鸡 - 怎么样?
- Oh, look at you. - Heh?
他喜欢我
He likes me.
哦 抱歉 波立特通常不啄人
Oh, oh! I'm sorry. Pollito is usually very friendly.
他昨晚过得不好
He had a rough night.
我们该走了 姑娘们 快点
Well, we really should be going. Girls, come on.
太可惜了
That is a pity.
年轻的爱是美丽的 不是吗?
Young love is beautiful, no?
不是
No!
我是说 他们没恋爱 他们几乎不认识
You know, they're not in love. They hardly know each other.
你说的没错 蛋头
You are right, Cabeza de huevo.
他们必须进一步认识对方
They must get to know each other better!
安东尼奥 为什么不邀请你的女朋友和她家人
Antonio, why don't you invite your girlfriend and her family
来我们的五月五日节派对呢?
to our Cinco de Mayo party?
不用了
No, no.
好哎
Si!
什么 埃尔马乔?
I'm sorry, El Macho?
我们不是在莎莎舞事件后
Hadn't we eliminated him as a suspect
就已经排除他的嫌疑了吗?
after the whole salsa incident?
是 但有新进展
Yes, but there has been a new development,
我可以保证 他就是我们找的人
and I'm telling you, this is the guy.
你必须马上逮捕他
You need to arrest him immediately.
还有他那不安好心的迷人儿子
And his deviously charming son!
我非常确定他儿子也参与了
I'm pretty sure that the son is involved, too.
儿子 也参与了 你必须抓住儿子
The son, also! You got to get the son!
我认为儿子才是主谋
I think that the son is the mastermind!
那个眼神 他眼睛里
There's a look, there's a devilish look
那邪恶的神情 我不喜欢
in his eyes, and I don't like it!
好吧 但我没看到任何证据
Yes, but I don't really see any evidence.
证据啥的都是浮云 我相信我的直觉
Evidence, schmevidence. I go with my gut,
而我的直觉告诉我那个人就是埃尔马乔
and my gut tells me that this guy is El Macho.
把他铐起来 还有他儿子
Lock him up, lock up the son.
千万别漏了儿子 那孩子让我毛骨悚然
Don't forget about the son. The kid gives me the creeps!
哦 天啊 天啊
Oh, dear, dear, dear.
但是 说起不太疯狂的事
But, on the less crazy side of things,
格鲁在鹰发俱乐部发现了血清痕迹
Gru discovered traces of the serum at Eagle Hair Club!
有意思
Hmm, interesting.
是啊 你知道这是谁的功劳吗? 哈?
Yeah! And you know who made that happen? Huh?
这个家伙 搞定了 很厉害吧?
This guy. Nailed it. Amazing, right?
不 我是说 当然 但不是他 是埃尔马乔
No, I mean, sure. But it's not him, it is El Macho!
格鲁先生 拜托
Mr. Gru, please!
不 就是他 我会证明的
No! It is him, and I will prove it!
格鲁 别这样
Gru, come on!
他真的认为是埃尔马乔
He really thinks it's El Macho.
你觉得呢?
Can you tell?
哦 嗨
Oh. Whoo!
给我
Give me that!
坏蛋网
Bad network.
连接中断
Connect the interrupt
凯文 无线网断了
Kevin, the Wi-Fi's out!
凯文呢?
Kevin?
兰斯 你知道凯文去哪了?
Hey, Lance, where the heck is Kevin?
好了 我们得重新制定你们假期天数了
All right, we need to revisit the number of vacation days you guys get.
叫谁也找不到
I can't find anybody anymore.
格鲁 我是吉莉安
Gru, it's Jillian!
好消息
I've got good news!
我朋友莎伦和我一起来了
I have my friend Shannon here with me.
我想你们可以一起吃个饭
I was thinking you two could get some grub.
打破常规 顺其自然
You know, tear it up, see what happens!
开门
Open up!
啦啦啦啦啦...
La, la, la, la, la, la, la. . .
艾格尼丝 艾格尼丝 告诉吉莉安我不在
Agnes! Agnes, tell Jillian I'm not here.
格鲁不在
Gru's not here.
你确定?
Are you sure?
对 他刚告诉我的
Yes, he just told me!
嗯哼
uh- huh!
我是说 他没告诉我
I mean, no, he didn't just tell me.
艾格尼丝 格鲁在哪?
Agnes, where is Gru?
涂口红呢
He's putting on lipstick!
拍苍蝇呢
He's swatting at flies!
不对 不对
No! No!
他砍自己的脑袋呢
He's chopping his head off!
他在拉便便?
He's pooping?
我知道你在里面 格鲁
I know you're in there, Gru!
这次你别想逃掉
There's no way you're getting out of this!
我必须告诉你 我今晚非常紧张
I have to tell you, I was so nervous about tonight.
我是说这年头骗子真是太多了
I mean there's just so many phonies out there!
嗯 我懂你
Yes, I hear you.
那么 你健身吗?
Oh, so, do you work out?
这个...
Well. . .
我是说 很显然你没有 但你会考虑吗?
I mean, obviously, you don't, but would you consider it?
啊? 身体健康对莎伦来说非常重要
Huh? Physical fitness is very important to Shannon.
你看得出来 对吧? 啊?
As you can tell, right? Huh?
哈
Ah.
现在看出来了
I can tell.
结实
Solid.
我们可是在餐馆呢
We are in the restaurant, you know.
- 嗨 - 露西的外卖?
- Hi. - Takeout for Lucy?
好的 稍等
Sure, just a sec.
你的口音太有异国风情了
Your accent is so exotic.
啊 谢谢夸奖
Ah. Well, thank you very much.
我认识熟人能给你治好
I know someone who can fix that for you.
你立马就能正常说话了
And you'll be talking normal in no time!
呜 这里很热吗?
Whoo. Is it hot in here?
东西好吃吗?
How's the food?
慢着 慢着 你戴着假发吗?
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Are you wearing a wig?
什么?
What?
啊 没有啊
Ah! I don't think so.
我就知道
I knew it.
你是个骗子 我恨骗子
You're a phony. I hate phonies!
什么? 不 这些头发都是我的
Oh, what? No. These locks are all mine.
它们不是
No, they're not!
你知道我要干嘛吗? 我要把那玩意从你头上扯下来
You know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna rip that thing off your head,
让大家都知道你是个秃头的骗子
and show everyone what a bald-headed phony you are.
不可能的 小姐
I don't think so, Miss Lady.
喂?
Hello?
喂? 你...
Hello? Are you. . .
嘿 格鲁
Hey, Gru.
你好 露西 怎么样啊?
Hello, Lucy. How are you doing?
看来你的约会对象晕过去了
Wow, looks like your date's out for the count.
貌似是被温和的驼鹿镇定剂射中了
It's like she's been shot with a mild moose tranquilizer.
我眨眼是因为确实如此
Yeah, I'm winking because that's what actually happened.
对不起 发生什么事了? 她不喜欢吗?
Scusi, what's happening here? She no like?
她只是 呃...
Oh, she's just, uh. . .
哦 呵呵
Oh, ho.
懂了 懂了
Understand understand.
要把她弄回家吗?
Shall we take her home?
哦
Oh!
好吧 你做到了 你刚正式经历了史上最差的约会
Well, I think you did it. You just officially had the worst date ever.
哈 可不是嘛
Huh, tell me about it.
别担心 从此只会走上坡了 对吧?
Don't worry. It can only get better from here, right?
如果不是的话 随时可以借我的镖枪
But if it doesn't, you can always borrow my dart gun.
我自己约会的时候也用过一两次
I've had to use it on one or two dates myself.
这个嘛 约会这种事
Yeah, you know, as far as dates go,
我想这一次就够了
I think I'm good with just the one.
那晚安了 伙伴
Well, good night, partner.
今晚非常有趣
This was fun.
是啊 出人意料的确实如此
Yes. Surprisingly, it was.
还有 我们之间的秘密?
Oh, and, uh, just between you and me?
你还是秃头好看一些
You look much better bald.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
呱 呱 呱 呱 呱
Quack, quack, quack, quack, quack!
耶
Yay!
看来约会非常顺利?
So, I take it the date went well?
不 糟糕至极
No, it was horrible.
击掌
High-five!
碰屁股
Bump it.
斯波顿先生?
Mr. Ramsbottom?
你好
Oh, hello.
你们在干嘛?
What are you doing here?
- 我们抓到他了 - 谁啊?
- We got him. - Got who?
是弗洛伊德·依格桑干的
Floyd Eaglesan!
我们的探员昨晚在他店里找到一间密室
Our agents located a secret room in his shop last night
然后发现了这个
and discovered this.
是空的 但我们发现了PX-41血清的痕迹
It's empty, but we found traces of the PX-41 serum in it.
他就是我们要找的人
He's our man.
不论如何 尽管你不称职 我们解决问题了
So, somehow, in spite of your incompetence, we solved this one.
我是被陷害的
I was framed!
你们不会有好下场的
You won't get away with this!
把手放开 我可是合法商人
Get your mitts off of me! I am a legitimate businessman.
好吧 现在呢?
Ah. All right. So what now?
现在你可以继续你的生意了
Well, now you're free to go back to your business.
嗯 果酱和果冻
Mmm. Jams and jellies.
而维尔德探员会被派到
And it looks like Agent Wilde will be
我们的澳大利亚分局
transferring to our Australian branch.
澳大利亚?
Australia?
是的
Yes.
但谢谢你所做的
But thank you for everything.
而你所做的 当然是无所作为
And by everything, of course I mean nothing.
再见冤家 加油了 格鲁先生
Toodle pip and cheerio, Mr. Gru.
- 你好啊 - 嘿
- Hey, there. - Hey.
我们抓到他了
So, we got him.
是啊 太棒了
Yay. That's great.
现在你要去澳大利亚了?
And now you're going to Australia?
还没最终确定 我仍然在考虑
Well, it's not definite yet. I'm still figuring it out.
不过我已经在练习口音了
I've already been working on my accent.
小袋鼠 迪吉里杜管(澳大利亚土著使用的一种乐器)
Wallaby. Didgeridoo.
休·杰克曼(澳大利亚男影星)
Hugh Jackman.
所以 呃... 蛮兴奋的
So, um...pretty excited.
那就好
Great.
那祝你好运
Well, good luck.
谢谢 你也是
Thanks. You, too.
哦 我想把这个给你
Oh! Here. I wanted to give you this.
你的口红镭射枪?
Your lipstick taser?
嗯 当作纪念吧
Yeah, it's just a memento.
从我们第一次见面到现在
Just, you know, from the first time we met.
谢谢 露西
Oh. Thank you, Lucy.
维尔德探员
Agent Wilde.
他们好像需要你 所以...
Well, it looks like they need you, so. . .
是啊 我最好过去了
Yeah, I better go.
再见 格鲁
Bye, Gru.
我给你带伞来了
I brought you an umbrella.
啊 谢谢
Ah, thank you.
你在外面做什么?
What are you doing out here?
记得你说我喜欢露西吗?
Remember when you said that I liked Lucy?
最后我才意识到
Well, it turns out,
你说对了
you're right.
真的?
Really?
对 但是...
Yes, but. . .
她要走了
Well, she's moving away.
我再也见不到她了
I'm never going to see her again.
有什么我能做的吗?
Is there anything I could do to help?
噢 我... 我觉得没有 亲爱的
Aw, I don't...I don't think so, sweetheart.
那有什么你能做的吗?
Well, is there anything you could do?
你好 露西 我是格鲁
Hello, Lucy. This is Gru.
我知道到目前为止我们的关系
I know up to this point our relationship
都是严格的工作需求
has been strictly professional,
而你要去澳大利亚了 但是...
and you're leaving for Australia and all, but. . .
好吧 我想问你
Okay, here is the question.
你愿意...
Would you like to. . .
和我约会吗?
to go out on a date?
呃 不愿意
Uh, no.
你这是在帮倒忙
Okay, that's not helping.
好了 开始了 这次是真的
All right, here we go. For real this time.
我可以的
I can do this.
啊 我恨你
Agh! I hate you!
啊
Ah.
火警
»ð¾¯
也不错
Eh.
- 凯文? - 嗯?
- Kevin? - Mmm?
汤姆吗?
Tom?
你好啊
Hello!
- 干杯 - 干杯
- Kampai! - Kampai!
啊? 干杯
Huh? Kampai!
五月五日节 五月五日节
Cinco de May-ya-yo! Cinco de May-ya-yo!
这儿好棒
This place is awesome!
好了 开始狂欢吧?
Okay. Let's party, huh?
不过首先 咱得再重申下规矩
But first, let's go over the rules.
没规矩 怎么有乐子呢 对吧?
Because what is fun without the rules?
艾格尼丝 油条悠着点儿吃
Agnes, easy on the churros.
- 伊迪丝 不要伤到别人 - 好
- Edith, try not to kill anyone. - Hai!
还有玛尔戈
Margo!
你好呀 格鲁先生
Hello, Mr. Gru.
好了
Okay.
喂 格鲁
Gru!
你必须和男生保持6英尺的距离
There must be the standard 6 feet of space between you and boys.
特别是这位
Especially this boy.
您真有趣
Ah, you are a funny man.
长官 这儿可没什么规矩 今天是五月五日节嘛
There are no rules, se? or. It's Cinco de Mayo.
来吧 要开始跳舞了
Come on! They're starting the dance!
好耶
Arriba!
朋友 您愿意来 我真高兴
So glad you could make it, mi compadre.
嘿 怎么了?
Hey, what's wrong?
没什么 什么事都没有
Oh, nothing. Nothing is wrong.
我只是在品味饼干帽里的鳄梨酱
I'm just chilling with the guac, from my chip hat.
拜托 格鲁 这种表情我太熟悉了
Gru, please. I know that look all too well.
这是心碎的表情
It is the look of a broken heart.
你怎么知道?
How did you know?
朋友 相信我吧 我也曾夜夜无眠
Believe me, my friend, I too have spent many nights
将自己的伤心事深埋在鳄梨酱中
trying to drown my sorrows in guacamole.
- 你? - 当然
- You? - Yes.
不过我们都是过来人
But we are survivors.
咱们都是有故事的人呐
There's much more to us than meets the eye.
玩得开心
Enjoy the party.
什么?
Say what?
您想要花生还是脆饼?
Would you like some peanuts or pretzels?
真好笑
That's a good joke.
我刚便便过
I just did a boom boom.
小姐 请快选一样吧
I really need you to make a choice, hon.
我选格鲁
I choose Gru.
I choose Gru!
谢谢你 空姐格鲁
Thank you, Gru stewardess!
别客气
You're welcome!
宝刀未老呀 朋友
You have not lost your touch, my friend.
啊哈 我就知道
Ah-ha! I knew it!
你是埃尔马乔
You are El Macho!
没错
That's right!
没人相信我
Nobody believed me!
吼吼 但我知道 你没死
Ho-ho! But I knew you weren't dead!
当然啦 那只是我假死
Of course not. I merely faked my death.
但是现在 我要
But now, it's time for me
高调回归坏人界了
to make a spectacular return to evil.
博士 该给格鲁展示下我们现在的工作了
Doctor, I think it's time we showed Gru what we're up to here.
尼法里奥博士?
Dr. Nefario?
格鲁 很高兴见到你
Nice to see you, Gru.
什么...?
Wha...?
这就是你的新工作?
So, this is your new job opportunity?
没错 你一定会喜欢这个
Absolutely. You're gonna like this.
抱歉
Sorry.
我迫不得已借了你几个仆从 不过绝对很值当
I had to borrow some of your minions, but it was for a worthy cause.
噢 凯文
Oh! Kevin!
不 他不再是凯文了
No, he's not Kevin anymore.
他现在是坚不可摧的盲目屠杀机器
Now he is an indestructible, mindless killing machine!
来看看吧
Just watch this.
给你看最厉害的
And here's the best part!
我有一整团这样的
I got an army of them!
看看吧
Look, look, look!
不久后 我就会把他们放出去
Soon I will unleash them on the world,
如果有谁想来阻止他们...
and if anyone, anyone tries to stop them. . .
就把他们的城市都吃掉
Their city gets eaten!
咱们可以合伙
We can do it together.
合伙?
Together?
合伙
Together!
朋友 我一直很欣赏你这些年的工作
I have admired your work for years, amigo.
偷月亮 那是真的吗?
Stealing the Moon! Are you kidding?
无人能阻挡我们
We would be unstoppable!
像你我这样的人物
Men like you, men like me.
我们就应该统治整个世界
We should be ruling the world!
你要加入吗?
So, are you in?
呃 可能吧
Uh, yeah, probably.
可能?
Probably?
我是想说 加入 当然加入了
I mean, yes, yes! Of course, yes.
只是我现在正好有些事情
I just have a lot going on right now.
只是我要先去飞碟上拿点东西
I just need to get some things off my plate
然后咱们再开始接管整个世界 仅此而已
before we start taking over the world, that's all.
- 什么? - 没事 什么都没说
- Excuse me? - No, forget it.
我加入 百分百加入
One hundred percent! I am in!
我只是觉得... 听到了吧? 我听到了
I think...Do you hear that? I do.
肯定是艾格尼丝在上面叫我呢
That's Agnes calling me from on the surface.
绝对加入
Totally in!
你知道吗?
You know what?
我不太肯定他会加入呢
I am not so convinced that he is in.
伊迪丝 艾格尼丝 过来 噢
Edith, Agnes, come on! Ooh!
抱歉
sorry.
我们现在就要回家了 玛尔戈人呢?
We need to go home now. Where is Margo?
但是还没轮到过我玩呢
But I didn't get a turn!
嘿 玛尔戈
Margo!
来 我们要走了...
Come on. We're leaving. . .
怎么了?
Hey, what's wrong?
我讨厌男生
I hate boys.
恩 男生真讨厌
Yes. They stink.
但是宝贝 咱们得走了
Uh, sorry. Honey, we got to go.
噢 不好意思
Oops! Sorry.
嘿 波立特 怎么了?
Hey! Pollito, what's the matter?
嘿 爱德华多
Oh, hey, Eduardo!
我替它道歉 露西
Lucia, I apologize.
波立特他平时不是这样的
Pollito, he's usually not like this.
前几天他见格鲁也是突然大变样...
The same thing happened the other day with Gru, and. . .
说到格鲁 你有看到他吗? 我有话跟他说
Oh, well, speaking of Gru, um, have you seen him? I really need to talk to him.
嗯 他肯定是在这儿
Yes. I think he's somewhere around here.
你俩关系很不错吧?
You two are close, no?
我也说不好
Oh, I don't know.
也不能说是关系不错
I mean, "close, " I wouldn't say we were close.
你为什么说 是他说的我们关系不错?
Why, did he say we were close? Did he say that?
他没说的可多了去了
It's more what he didn't say.
就比如 他从来没提到过
For instance, he never mentioned
你俩都在为反恶联盟工作
that you were both working for the Anti-Villain League!
你给我过来
You're coming with me.
嘿
Hey!
呀
Crikey!
所以爱德华多真的是埃尔马乔?
So, Eduardo's actually El Macho?
哇哦
Cool!
一点都不值得哇哦
No, it is not cool!
另外 我一直都知道是他
Plus, I pretty much knew it was him all along,
所以只有我才值得哇哦
so if anyone's cool, it's me!
嘿 格鲁
Gru!
尼法里奥博士
Well, Dr. Nefario.
埃尔马乔在找你 他知道你在为反恶联盟工作
El Macho's onto you. He knows you're working for the AVL.
还抓到了你的拍档
And he's got your partner.
是露西?
Lucy?
不可能 她正去往澳大利亚
That's impossible. She's on her way to Australia!
尼法里奥 你在哪儿?
Nefario?
抱歉 先闪了
Sorry, gotta go!
他抓走了露西?
He's got Lucy?
抓不了多久
Not for long.
过来 我们去救她出来
Come on, we're getting her out of there.
什么声音?
What was that?
没什么东西呀
I don't see anything.
快跑
Run!
我的独角兽
My unicorn!
艾格尼丝 别去
Agnes, no!
来 快
Come on! Hurry!
怎么了?
What's the matter?
是凯文
Kevin!
尼法里奥博士 你回来啦
Dr. Nefario! You're back!
就是我
In the flesh.
看 还有解药
Behold, the antidote.
来 咱们终于要让这些恐怖的果酱派上些用途了
Come on. Let's finally put this horrible jelly to some good use.
喂 你们 拜托 都专心点
Hey, guys, come on! Stay focused here.
你们这些家伙 又被打败了吧
Curses! Foiled again!
这俩家伙逮捕了我
These guys captured me!
跑啊
Run!
上树
Up that tree!
快点 快点
Hurry! Hurry!
你好 格鲁
Hello, Gru!
嘿 干得好 尼法里奥博士
Hey hey! Nice work, Dr. Nefario!
我在果酱里放了解药
I put an antidote in the jelly.
我很乐意创造一支坏人军队毁灭整个世界
I mean, I'm happy to create an evil army to destroy the world,
但绝不能伤害我的家人
but nobody messes with my family.
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, Doctor.
就让我们一起去...
Now, let's go get the. . .
嗨
Hi!
你把孩子们也带来了?
You brought the girls?
对啊
Yes!
有什么问题吗?
Was that wrong?
我的仆从都怎么了?
What's happening to my minions?
是格鲁?
Gru?
你们去料理下其他的仆从
You guys, take care of the rest of the minions.
我去找露西
I'm going to find Lucy.
吃果酱吧 你们这些小紫人
Eat jelly, you purple freaks!
都结束了 埃尔马乔
It's over, El Macho.
露西在哪里?
Now, where is Lucy?
我来给你看看
Let me show you.
嘿 格鲁
Oh, hey, Gru!
看来你说的埃尔马乔的事儿都对了哈?
Turns out you were right about the whole El Macho thing, huh?
耶
Yay!
只要摁下这个键 我就能让火箭
One push of this button, and I send that rocket
再次发射到我假死的那个火山口里
straight into the same volcano where I faked my death.
只不过这次就是真死了
Only this time, it's for real.
不要
No!
格鲁 你我本可以携手统治整个世界的
We could have ruled the world together, Gru!
但现在
But now,
你要死了
you're gonna die.
口红镭射枪
Mmm, lipstick taser!
他学我的
Aw, he copied me.
我可不怕你们的果酱枪
I am not afraid of your jelly guns.
这可不是果酱枪 这是气枪
Oh, this ain't a jelly gun, sunshine.
格鲁 不用担心我 我没事
Don't worry about me, Gru, I'll be fine.
比这更恶劣的境况下 我都活过来了
I have survived lots worse than this.
好吧 这句不是实话
Okay, that's not entirely true.
其实我吓得要死了
I'm actually kind of freaking out up here!
别怕 我这就救你出来
Don't worry, I will get you out of this.
我真的很讨厌这只鸡
I really hate that chicken.
有红的吗? 真的有条红的
Is there a red one? It's usually the red one!
格鲁 没时间了
Gru, anytime now!
露西 听我说 这次我们可能不能活着脱险了
Listen, Lucy, we may not get out of this alive,
所以我一定要问你一个问题
so I need to ask you a question.
最好快点问
Uh, better make it quick.
如果我邀你出去约会 你会怎么回答?
If I had asked you out on a date, what would you have said?
真的吗?
Are you kidding me?
当然是可以
Yes!
跳
Jump!
露西 你在哪儿
Lucy!
露西 你在哪儿?
Lucy, where are you?
噢 露西
Oh, Lucy!
噢 格鲁
Gru!
抱歉 忘了你胳膊还得用来划水
Sorry! I guess you need your arms to tread water, huh?
他们还会回来找的
They'll be back.
147次约会后
Date after 147.
我要第一个说"呦 "
Can I be the first to say, "Ew! "
好吧
Okay.
抱歉
Excuse me.
各位 抱歉
Um, hi, excuse me.
嗨 各位 我想说些祝酒词
Hi, everybody. I'd like to make some toast.
好吧
Okay.
她 呃...
She, um. . .
她会亲吻我的小伤口 还会帮我编头发
She kisses my boo-boos, she braids my hair.
我们爱你 天下所有的妈妈
We love you, mothers, everywhere.
还有我的新妈妈 露西 是天下最好的妈妈
And my new mom, Lucy, is beyond compare.
为新娘和格鲁举杯
To the bride and Gru!
我太开心啦
Woo-hoo! I'm so happy!
不要走开 精彩继续
Don't go away,Wonderful to continue.
嘿 鲍勃 图尔特
Hey, Bob! Stuart!
小黄人电影试镜
Minion film audition
不好吗?
No?
都是你 鲍勃
Bob!
好了
Okay.
笨蛋
Blah.